Quan Guo

PhD candidate at Georgia Institute of Technology

Email: qguo48@gatech.edu or qguo48@hotmail.com

Website: https://quanguo.github.io
LinkedIn | GitHub | Publications

Office: 790 Atlantic Dr NW, Atlanta, GA, 30332. Jesse W. Mason Building, Room 2230.

Objectives

I am a passionate **cross-disciplinary** researcher in **physics** and **machine learning**, dedicated to utilizing AI and machine learning to solve scientific problems and construct digital twins. My current research focuses on several key areas:

- **Physics-Informed Neural Networks**: Developing neural networks with combining physics-based knowledge to enhance predictive robustness.
- **Neural Operators and Surrogate Forward Models**: Exploring the use of neural operators to efficiently simulate complex physical processes.
- AI Generative Modeling: Implementing AI generative model for encoding complicated subsurface structures. Combine AI generative model and traditional sampling and optimization of inverse estimation.
- Bayesian Analysis and Random Fields: Employing Bayesian analysis and random fields to model uncertainty and variability in geospatial data.
- **High-Performance Computing**: Utilizing high-performance computing resources to expedite data processing and model training.

Education

School	Degree	Major	GPA	Time
Georgia Institute of Technology	Ph.D	Civil Engineering	3.96/4.00	Jan 2019 – Apr 2024
Georgia Institute of Technology	MS	Computer Science	3.96/4.00	Aug 2017 – Dec 2018
Georgia Institute of Technology	MS	Environmental Engineering	3.90/4.00	Aug 2016 – Dec 2017
Xiamen University	BS	Ecology	3.28/4.00	Sep 2012 - May 2016

Teaching

Georgia Institute of Technology

Head Teaching Assistant of CSE 6250 Big Data for Healthcare

Since 2020

Lab Instructor CEE 4200 Hydraulic Engineering

Spring 2019, Spring 2020

Research Projects

- Assimilated multi-source IoT data from well-logs with **Physics Informed Neural Network** for reservoir inference, achieving equal accuracy as the best numerical model but 10x faster.
- Developed **Fourier Neural Operator (FNO)** as surrogate geophysical model and combined FNO and **PCA** for subsurface inverse modeling with borehole hydraulic data, model is 30x faster than numerical model.
- Developed **GAN** and **DNN** inference model of 2D reservoir with **Tensorflow** to estimate the subsurface fracture based on well test data for discovery, making the first deep learning model for this task.
- Combined **PCA** and **geostatistical approach** to develop efficient numerical inverse model for groundwater modeling and uncertainty quantification with pumping test data, shortening the modeling time from 18 days to 1 hours.
- Applied upscaling method to develop high-speed numerical PDE solvers and geophysical simulation models with MATLAB, enhancing the simulation speed by 16x with approximation error <3%.
- Combined **snesim** based on **multiple-point statistics** and Monte Carlo sampling to generate subsurface fractured realizations conditioning on borehole data. Provided estimation of the CO₂ storage capacity.

Work Experiences

Schlumberger-Doll Research

Cambridge, MA

Research Intern as Machine Learning Engineer

May 2023 - Aug 2023

 $Find\ end\ to\ end\ AI\ solution\ for\ carbon\ capture\ and\ sequestration\ in\ 3D\ subsurface\ environment.$

• Developed "GeoGPT" software with the StyleGAN-V at backend, providing real-time uncertainty identification of CO₂ storage in reservoirs. Users can make quotes and obtain prompt responses.

- Built an AI/ML pipeline on Azure DevOps to automate the data loading and model training.
- Designed and encapsulated the state-of-art neural network modules that users, with or without AI background, can customize an AI model within one-line code and leverage CUDA and DL pipeline to train.

Ping An Insurance Co.

Beijing, China

May 2018 - July 2018

Machine learning engineering

Develop machine learning models for disease prediction.

- Detected risks of diabetes by conducting quantitative analysis on time series data of daily body checks.
- Performed A/B tests and analysis of significant difference to assess the impact of a diabetes treatment.

Skills

Programming: Python, Java, C/C++, MATLAB **Big Data**: PySpark, Hadoop, Scala, Hive, Pig, Hbase

Cloud Computing: AWS, Azure, Google Cloud Platform, LAMBDA

Data Analysis: R, MySQL, Numpy, Pandas

ML/DL/AI: CUDA, Pytorch, Tensorflow, Scikit-learn, Comet-ML

CI/CD: Git, Docker, Azure DevOps, Google Container Registry, Bitbucket, Gitlab

Publications

Peer-reviewed journals

- Guo, Q., Liu, M., & Luo, J. (2023), Predictive Deep Learning for High-Dimensional Inverse Modeling of Hydraulic Tomography in Gaussian and Non-Gaussian Fields, *Water Resour. Res.*, 59(10), e2023WR035408, doi: https://doi.org/10.1029/2023WR035408.
- Guo, Q., Zhao, Y., Lu, C., & Luo, J. (2023). High-dimensional inverse modeling of hydraulic tomography by physics informed neural network (HT-PINN). *Journal of Hydrology*, 616, 128828, doi: https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhydrol.2022.128828.
- Zhao, Y., Guo, Q., Lu, C., & Luo, J. (2022). High-dimensional groundwater flow inverse modeling by upscaled effective model on principal components. *Water Resour. Res.*, 58(7), e2022WR032610. doi: https://doi.org/10.1029/2022WR032610.
- He, Y., Guo, Q., Liu, Y., Huang, H., Hou, D., & Luo, J. (2024). Multiphysics Modeling Investigation of Wellbore Storage Effect and Non-Darcy Flow. Water Resources Research, 60(1), e2023WR035453. doi: https://doi.org/10.1029/2023WR035453.
- Guo, Q., He, Y., Liu, M., Zhao, Y., Liu, Y., & Luo, J. Fourier neural operator for deep learning surrogate model of subsurface flow. [under review]

Conferences

• [Presentation] Guo, Q., Luo, J. Large-scale Inverse Modeling of Hydraulic Tomography by Physics Informed Neural Network, In: AGU 2022 Fall Meeting, Chicago, IL, December 2022

Invited Talks and Seminars

- Scalable high-dimensional inverse modeling of hydraulic tomography by physics informed neural network (HT-PINN). In: National Environmental Conference for Doctoral Students, Beijing, China, January 2023.
- Physics informed neural network in groundwater inverse modeling. In: Water Resource Engineering Seminar, Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA, March 2022.

Service and Leadership

- Currently served as reviewer for Water Resources Research, Journal of Hydrology, etc.
- President of Student Association, College of Environment and Ecology, Xiamen University